WeiQin Chuah

Portfolio: linkedin.com/weiqin Github: github.com/weiqin

ABOUT ME

A self-motivated and enthusiastic final-year PhD candidate at RMIT University, Australia. Research interests include machine learning, computer vision, autonomous navigation, and robotics. Current research focuses on synthetic-to-realistic domain generalization for deep learning-based computer vision problems such as stereo matching, optical flow and semantic segmentation. The developed systems will be highly beneficial for real-life applications such as autonomous driving, robotics, augmented reality and more.

EDUCATION

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

PhD - Mechanical, Manufacturing and Mechatronics Engineering (Expected to graduate in December 2022)

Melbourne, Australia Feb 2019 - Current

Email: weiqin5645@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 424 095 691

Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

Bachelor of Engineering (Adv. Manufacturing and Mechatronics) (Honours). [GPA: 3.7]

Melbourne, Australia Mar 2014 - Nov 2018

Monash College

Monash University Foundation Year (MUFY). [WAM: 83.0]

Melbourne, Australia Jan 2012 - Oct 2012

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash

Frameworks: Pandas, Scikit, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch
 Tools/Software: Docker, GIT, Jupyter, Carla, CATIA, Solidworks
 Platforms: Linux, Windows, macOS, Arduino, AWS

Publications

• An Information-Theoretic Method to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization for Dense Prediction Tasks

Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI) 2022

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• ITSA: An Information-Theoretic Approach to Automatic Shortcut Avoidance and Domain Generalization in Stereo Matching Networks

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2022

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar, D Suter

• Semantic Guided Long Range Stereo Depth Estimation for Safer Autonomous Vehicle Applications
IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2022

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, D Suter, A Bab-Hadiashar

• Deep Learning-Based Incorporation of Planar Constraints for Robust Stereo Depth Estimation in Autonomous Vehicle Applications

IEEE Transactions on Itelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 2021

WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

Machine Vision-Enabled Traffic Controller for Safer and Smoother Traffic Flow Around Construction Sites
 IEEE Intelligent Transportation Systems Conference (ITSC) 2019 WQ Chuah, R Tennakoon, R Hoseinnezhad, A Bab-Hadiashar

• State Transition for Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds

Sensors, Volume 19, Issue 1614, 2019

AK Gostar, C Fu, WQ Chuah, MI Hossain, R Tennakoon, A Bab-Hadiashar, R Hoseinnezhad

Professional Experience

RMIT University

Melbourne, Australia Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

Mechatronics Engineering Intern (Machine Learning, Image Processing, Sensor Fusion)
Research and development of an intelligent cow screening and cleaning system

- o Point cloud re-projection from RGB-D images
- o 3D reconstruction via point cloud registration and stitching using iterative closest point
- $\circ\,$ Sensor fusion using data collected from thermal sensor and RGB-D cameras
- $\circ\,$ Develop a machine learning model for healthy or diseased classification

Aubot

Melbourne, Australia Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

Mechanical Engineer Intern (Mechanical Design)

Research and development of a 6 degree of freedom assistant robotic arm, Jeva

 \circ Design and prototyping of robotic grippers using 3D CAD modeling in Solidworks

Machine Learning (COSC2673)

Tutor / Lab Demonstrator

RMIT University

Feb 2021 - Current

- This course introduces the fundamental Machine Learning concepts, covering supervised and unsupervised techniques, evaluation, as well as specific approaches such as deep neural networks.
- Reinforce the theoretical understanding of Machine Learning concepts introduced in the lecture; and assist students with applying theory concepts into programming practice for solving a wide range of problems, using open source Machine Learning toolkits.

Digital Fundamentals (OENG1206)

RMIT University

Feb 2021 - July 2021

Lab Demonstrator

- This course is focused on digital literacies for engineers and will equip the students with the ability to apply a problem-solving methodology to common engineering problems.
- $\circ\,$ Guide students to design, write, test and debug programs to solve a variety of engineering problems using MATLAB/Simulink.

Mechatronics Principle (MIET2370)

RMIT University

Teaching Assistant

Feb 2020 - July 2020

- This course introduces the principle of Mechatronics as a multidisciplinary engineering discipline that includes electronics, electrical, mechanical, computer systems engineering, together with information technology.
- Provide students with hands-on assistance in putting theory into practice in the context of a challenging project that is at the core of a national design and build competition (NI ARC)

PROJECTS

RMIT University

Melbourne, Australia

Wide Baseline Stereo Data Collection (Data acquisition, System Integration)

May 2019 - April 2020
Real-time driving imageries data collection using multiple cameras, LiDAR and GPS sensor.

- Software: Data acquisition using C++/Python with dedicated SDK for sensors; Sensor synchronization to minimize data misalignment; Real-time data visualization
- $\circ\,$ Hardware: Integrating all sensors and electronics as a system on a moving vehicle
- o Data post-processing: stereo rectification and data alignment between RGB images and LiDAR points

RMIT University

Melbourne, Australia

Mar 2017 - Oct 2018

Mechatronics Final Year Projects (Computer Vision, Robotics)

Development of Statistical SLAM Using Planar Features in 3D Point Clouds

• Plane segmentation using a robust statistical estimator

- Noises/outliers removal using RANSAC
- Point cloud registration and map generation
- o Path planning and motion control

Extracurricular Experience

High Powered Rocket Team - HIVE RMIT

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

Recovery Systems Team Leader

Develop a reliable rocket recovery system to allow sufficient drag and counteract the force of gravity for minimizing the landing impact. The main tasks involve:

- $\circ\,$ Selecting appropriate parachute dimensions and design.
- $\circ~$ Setting a suitable deployment mechanism.
- $\circ\,$ Integrating multiple electronic sensors for real-time tracking of the deployed rocket.

Our team won the first place in the Australian Universities Rocket Competition in the 30,000ft category in 2019.

RMIT Mates Program

Feb 2016 - Oct 2016

Volunteer Mentor

Provide practical advice, social interaction and general academic guidance to newly-arrived international, regional or rural/remote students in their first semester of study at RMIT University.

RMIT Student Learning Advisor Mentors (SLAMs)

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016

Volunteer Mentor

Provide academic advice and share strategies with students on time management and study planning to achieve outstanding results.

Referees

Available upon request.